Nice to meet the pride of Trois-Rivieres.
很高兴见到Trois-Rivieres的大人物
I still got your Wings rookie card.
我还有你做红翼队菜鸟的卡片呢
So what's that worth? It's a collector's item.
- 有何价值 - 收藏者的爱好
They don't make them like you anymore. So do you wanna go?
- 现在都不出这种卡片了 - 来不来?
Square up. Good luck.
准备好了 祝你好运
He didn't get a hand on you?
他都没碰你一下吗?
You're going to be a force in the show.
这下你要成大明星了
Get a trainer over here!
把教练叫过来
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第16集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第16集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：ID 校对：ID 时间轴：绿
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：fflonestar 墨墨塔 校对：你加班来我死宅 时间轴：绿
i>Capacity crowd is on its feet. Five seconds on the clock.
全场观众都站了起来 时间还剩下5秒
How is it possible for one man to be blessed with so much skill?
怎么会有人如此的天赋异丙啊
I had one just like this, except it was Bruins and the Habs.
我也有一台这个 只不过是棕熊和蒙特利尔队的
Where did you get it? Birthday present for someone in pediatric oncology.
- 你从哪儿弄来的 - 小儿肿瘤科某人的生日礼物
22-year-old enforcer with hemoptysis.
22岁"执法人"咳血 (每支球队都有一个专门负责打架的球员)
He's a hockey player? No, he's a superhero.
- 他是冰球运动员? - 不 他是超级英雄
He's coughing up blood because he probably broke a rib and punctured a lung
他咳血很可能是在以运动的名义 企图打断别人肋骨 打伤别人肺部时
while breaking someone else's rib and puncturing their lung in the name of sport.
自己的肋骨断掉 肺部受伤
Nice conclusion to which the E.R. already jumped 18 hours ago.
总结得好 急诊那边18小时前就已经这么说了
Short man equals bullied child.
小矮子就是要被欺负
I was average height as a kid and never bullied.
我小时候是中等身高 并且从未被欺负过
???Until now.
直到现在
X- ray ruled out traumatic sequelae,
X光排除是创伤后遗症
overt TB, and lung cancer.
开放性肺结核 和肺癌
Sarcoidosis. Nodules could be too small to show up on an X-ray.
类肉瘤病 瘤块太小的话 X光是照不出来的
Fighting's the best part of hockey. Without it, you've got the Ice Capades.
打架是冰球最精彩的环节 少了这个 就跟白雪溜冰团一样了
Fighting has nothing to do with hockey. It's like the cheerleaders at a basketball game.
打架跟冰球毫无关系 就像篮球场上的啦啦队一样
Cheerleading's the best part of basketball.
啦啦队才是篮球比赛最好看的地方
Without it you've got... Basketball.
少了这个 就只剩下...篮球
He's a duck hunter.
他喜欢打鸭子
He could've contracted psittacosis from exposure to fowl.
有可能是因为与家禽接触 而感染了鹦鹉热
He had three teeth knocked out two weeks ago.
两周前他有三颗牙被打掉了
Infection could've led to oral bleeding. Not without continuing dental pain.
- 感染可能会导致口腔出血 - 但没有持续性的牙痛
Then he took an elbow to the gut, which caused an esophageal tear.
然后他的内脏被手肘撞到 造成食道破裂
Chase, CT the patient. Check for sarcoid.
Chase 给病人做CT 检查肉瘤
Adams, sputum cultures and serologies for psittacosis. Taub...
Adams 唾液培养 鹦鹉热血清 Taub...
I'd tell you why I think your theory
我本想告诉你 为何你的理论
is not just wrong but ill-conceived, but it's more fun to prove it
不仅错误 而且有病 不过更有趣的证明方法
by having you check the stool for blood.
是请你去验一下大便里有没有血
And while we wait for the stool fairy,
在等待"屎仙子"的同时呢
I'm a man down, so you want to drop your pants
我少了一个人 所以你想脱掉白大褂
and hit the ice.
来打冰球么
The faster you guys can do this, the better.
你们越快越好吧
The NHL's been sniffing around,
NHL正在四处纳新呢
and being in the hospital is not really helping my marketability.
躺在医院里可不会让我有什么市场
You have to be pretty good to get called up.
你一定很容易被激怒吧
Yeah, leading the league in penalty minutes.
是啊 在罚时的时候带领士气
And visits to the E.R., not counting the ones you've caused.
还有跑急诊室 不算你自己造成的那些
Not a hockey fan, I gather? I am. That's the point.
- 看来你不是冰球迷? - 我是 这才是重点
Fighting cheapens a great sport.
欺负弱小是多好一运动啊
Oh, come on, that's like saying passing cheapens football. It's part of the game.
拜托 你这就等于说是橄榄球赛上撞倒别人一样 这是比赛的一部分
I don't cause injuries. They're self-inflicted?
- 我没有制造伤害 - 那是他们自残的?
No, I prevent them.
不 我是避免伤害发生
I take the hit so the smaller guys don't have to.
我挨打 这样小个子的队员就不用受伤
I thought you'd appreciate that.
我以为这会令人感激呢
Neighbor's baby again?
邻居家孩子又闹了?
I could hear it through earplugs, two pillows,
我戴着耳塞 压着两个枕头
and three sleeping pills.
外加三颗安眠药 还是能听到
What is wrong with you?
你有什么毛病啊
I just said, "hmm. " You're trying to figure out
- 我就"嗯"了一声 - 你是想从我
some deeper significance to my having a couple of crappy nights.
几个夜晚的煎熬中挖掘出更深层的含义
Which one of us is analyzing the word "hmm" here?
咱俩是谁在这儿分析"嗯"这个字呢?
Fine. Sorry.
好吧 抱歉
Apology accepted.
接受道歉
However... Mm. It's not the crying that's keeping you awake.
不过呢 让你夜不能寐的并不是哭声
The sound of a needy child is stirring your paternal juices.
孩子哭喊的声音 让你父爱泛滥了
The sound of a needy child at 112 decibels has stirred my inner murderer.
高达112分贝的孩子哭喊声 唤醒了我内心的杀手
Don't mess with me. Explain the stains on your shirt.
- 你少搅和我 - 解释一下衬衣上的污渍
You're lactating.
你喷奶了
The fact that you're the only fruit on your family tree
你是家里唯一独苗苗的现实
is getting to you.
让你备受困扰
It's not a big deal.
这没什么大不了的
So I'll probably never be a dad.
我或许是一辈子都没机会当爹
It's- it sucks. I'll lose a little sleep, but-
很衰 我会失眠一下下 但是...
You're not supposed to feel bad when you dodge a bullet.
躲子弹的时候 是不该感到内疚的
It's like you got survivor's guilt.
你这是为自己活下来而内疚
There are actually things in this world that give life even more meaning
这世上有肥皂剧和怪物卡车以外的东西
than soap operas and monster trucks.
可以让生命更富有意义
And we happen to be missing out on at least one of them.
而我们不巧错过了很多
Remember the falconer?
还记得那个养鹰的么
Beth?
Beth?
You dated two falconers? Yes, Beth.
你约会过两个养鹰的? 就是 Beth
The night the two of you split up, you came around to my place,
你俩分手那晚 你到我家来
wallowing in self-pity and Tequila.
沉浸在自怜和龙舌兰之中
You passed out.
你昏睡过去
She called that night, asked me to give you a message.
那晚她打电话来 让我给你捎句话
She said she was pregnant...
她说自己怀孕了
Which, God and Planned Parenthood willing,
也就是 依照上帝和计划生育的旨意
means you are the father of an 11-year-old.
你现在是一个11岁孩子的爹了
I told you the next morning...
转天早上我跟你说过
Hypothetically.
打了个比方
I asked you how you'd feel if Beth had gotten pregnant, and you said, and I quote,
我问你如果Beth怀孕了你怎么办 你的原话是
"It would be the worst mistake of my life. "
"这会是我这辈子最严重的错误 "
And... Scene.
....停
Two performances Sunday, dark mondays?
周日演出两场 "黑色星期一"?
Just as well.
这样更好
I want to kill my mother.
我想杀了我妈妈
My Popo's on her own,
我外婆一个人生活
and my mother always needs me to take care of her.
我妈老是要我去照顾她
Well, you could kill Popo instead.
那你可以杀了外婆啊
I have to take her shopping, to her friends, to Atlantic City.
我得带她去买东西 送她去见朋友 去大西洋城
I love her, but every night, every weekend...
我爱她 可是每天晚上 每个周末
And only if there was some solution, someplace where you could live...
如果有什么办法可以解决 让你有个地方住
that's not there. My mom would freak.
- 离开家 - 我妈会疯掉的
It would be the ultimate sign of disrespect.
这绝对是大不敬
Okay. Then stay.
好吧 那就待着吧
And maybe you consider not bitching about it?
或许你可以考虑不要再抱怨?
Not everyone's lucky enough to have your independence.
不是每个人都那么幸运 可以独立生活的
Don't worry. When you lose your family, you'll have it too.
别担心 等你失去了家人 你也会独立的
He doesn't have sarcoid.
他没有类肉瘤
Look at that. That's his spleen.
- 你看啊 - 那是他的脾脏
I know.
我知道
But he's gotten it supersized.
可是也太大了吧
Deep vein thrombosis caused by any one of his many injuries or surgeries.
深静脉血栓可能是任何一次受伤或手术造成的
Leukemia's a better fit.
更像是白血病
We have a guy who is punishing his body on a daily basis.
咱们这个病人每天都在惩罚自己的身体
Don't you think that's a more likely cause than cancer?
你不觉得这比癌症更有可能吗
No, because she doesn't have an agenda.
不觉得 因为她不是别有用心
Well, that was incredibly unprofessional.
这么说也太不专业了吧
Well, it was really Taub's fault.
不过都是Taub的错
If you're not prepared to slam her into the boards, she's got no reason not to go after you.
如果你不想狠狠给她一击 她干嘛不先朝你下手啊
Might I suggest pulling her jersey over her head first?
我建议先用衣服罩住她的头 你说好不好
We should get an ultrasound for DVT and WBC for leukemia.
我们应该用超声波检查DVT 化验白细胞计数 看不是白血病
You think I could have cancer?
你们觉得我可能有癌症?
More likely, it's just a DVT.
更像是DVT
This is my agent. I gotta get this, man.
是我经纪人 我得接一下电话
Give me some good news, Kenny.
我要听好消息  Kenny
I thought you said any day.
你不是说随时都有可能吗
Okay.
好吧
I gotta go.
先挂了
I called Beth.
我打电话给Beth了
I have an 11-year-old son.
我有个11岁的儿子
Liver failure could alter hormone levels, cause abnormal breast development.
肝功能衰竭可能会改变荷尔蒙水平 引起不正常的胸部发育
Alcoholism.
酒精中毒
We should search his home and locker room.
咱们应该查一下他家和储物柜
Note that the person who wants to search the home didn't sleep in one last night.
发现想搜别人家的某同志 昨晚没在家里睡啊
You have the imprint of a seatbelt buckle in your cheek.
你脸上有安全带扣的引子
I got in a fight with my mother.
我跟我妈妈吵架了
She hit you with a seatbelt?
她用安全带抽你了?
Could be hemochromatosis.
可能是血色沉着病
Explains the liver and the spleen, but hemoptysis is a stretch.
可以解释肝脏和脾脏的问题 但咳血不太可能
What about leptospirosis?
那细螺旋体病呢
That's a good fit, if you ignore the fact that he's a pro athlete
这个很吻合 如果你忽略他是个职业运动员
who looks like the Incredible Hulk, which means he's gotta be on steroids,
身材健硕无比 也就是说他会用类固醇
which is a better fit.
这样更吻合
All we really know for sure is it was his evil job that caused the problems.
我们现在可以肯定的 是他的邪恶工作引起了这些问题
Yes, I don't like him. Doesn't mean my judgment's affected.
是 我不喜欢他 不代表我的判断会受影响
Maybe. Let's take a look at the instant replay.
也许吧 我们来看看即时重放
This is the hit that precipitated Booby Orr's fight.
这就是导致Booby Orr开打的那一撞 (Booby Orr 前加拿大职业冰球员)
Dirty or clean?
有没有猫腻?
The hit was clean. Really?
- 没有猫腻 - 真的吗
The guy released the puck at least a second before the hit.
这家伙在撞击前就把球饼放了出去
We have a difference of opinion. That's all.
我们意见不同 仅此而已
Absolutely.
当然
Maybe she's as biased as you. Or maybe the entire league is.
或者她也和你一样有偏见 或者整个联盟都有偏见呢
After review, the league disciplinary commissioner
不过在仲裁之后 联盟纪律委员会
ruled the hit illegal and dangerous and suspended the player for three games.
认定该触击违反规则而且危险 这名球员将禁赛三场
Adams and Taub, run antibody titers for lepto.
Adams和Taub 做钩端螺旋体病的抗体筛查
Chase and Park, check out the home, the locker room for booze, steroids,
Chase和Park 检查他家和更衣室 找有没有酒精和类固醇
and Taub's objectivity.
以及Taub的客观性
At least you're free. Going to get your own place?
至少你自由了吧 要自己租房子住了?
If I can find a place I can afford,
如果能找到我租得起的房才行
so... no.
所以...暂时还没有
If you want, you can crash at my place
如果你想 你可以先在我那边住着啊
in the spare bedroom.
我有个卧室是空的
That might be kind of weird.
那样不是有点奇怪吗
I live in an apartment, not a dungeon.
我住的是公寓 又不是地牢
It's just two single people, opposite sex. I-
孤男寡女 共处一室 这个...
Your bedroom door has a lock on the inside.
你的卧室是可以从里面上锁的
Hey, if you prefer your car, be my guest.
如果你喜欢睡在你的车里那也随便你
Scrip for Ganciclovir.
更昔洛韦的处方
If his neighbor has mono, could mean he has mono.
如果他旁边的人得了单核细胞增多症 那他也就会被传染上
If he has mono, explains his spleen and hemoptysis.
如果他有单核细胞增多症 那他的脾脏和咯血也就能解释了
And it's caused by Epstein-Barr virus,
而且由于这病本身是由Epstein-Barr病毒引起的
which explains his liver.
肝脏的情况也就得到解释了
And my moonroof leaks.
我车的顶棚漏雨
Thank you.
谢谢你了
Why don't we just assume that you're not the dad?
我们干嘛不先假设你不是他爹呢?
Either you're the dad, or she cheated on you with your dad.
啧啧 要么你是爹 要么她背着你和你爹搞过了
Oh! Sand art. I used to love this.
哎哟! 沙画 我小时候最喜欢这个了
He's bitter, not mentally handicapped.
他是有点苦逼 但智力还没缺陷好吗
Who knows what Beth told him about you? At worst, you're a rapist.
谁知道Beth都跟他怎么说你的 最坏的情况 说不定说你是个强奸犯呢
At best, you're a rapist.
最好的情况 你也就是一强奸犯了
Maybe she said I was a dead war hero.
说不定她说我是英勇牺牲的战斗英雄呢
Raised by a lunatic mother and abandoned by his father.
被神经病老妈养大再被亲爹抛弃
Oh, I know! Squirrel handcuffs. You think he's gotten any of those?
我知道了! 情趣手铐怎么样? 你觉得他有没有玩过那个?
If you really wanted me to do nothing with this information,
如果你真那么希望我对这个信息无动于衷的话
then why did you give it to me?
又干嘛要告诉我呢?
Because you were pining for a kid,
你想要娃子
and you deserved to know that you already had one.
所以你就应该知道你已经有个娃子了呗
But your parental cravings are more theoretical than applied.
但是你的父爱本能可是理论大于实际哟
You want vicarious immortality more than you want a lifelong burden.
你想要传宗接代的愿望远大于想要拥有终身负担的决心
You're assuming he's going to be a nightmare. What if he's a good kid?
你老是觉得他会是个小混蛋 如果他就是个好孩子呢?
He's a kid.
他是个孩子
Best you can hope for is he's a nightmare.
最好的情况下 也就是个小混蛋了
House, I'm not naive. I realize that this thing could go very badly,
House 我没那么天真 我早意识到这件事可能会有很糟的结果
but the point is my son wants to meet me.
但现在的问题是 我儿子想要见我
And I want to meet him.
而我也想要见他
Popo, I presume.
我猜你就是婆婆吧?
Hey, uh, I let myself in.
嘿 我自己开门进来了
Um, this is-
呃 这是-
We've met.
已经认识过了
I thought the whole point of this was to get away from Popo.
我以为你这么做的原因是因为你想离开外婆呢
My dad's getting a cyst removed, and my mother had to take him to the clinic.
我爸爸要做一个切除囊肿的小手术 我妈送他去诊所了
Don't worry. She'll be gone in an hour.
别担心 她就呆一个小时
I'm not worried, because it's not my issue.
我才不担心呢 又不是我的问题
She seems awfully quiet.
她有点太沉默寡言了吧?
You haven't seen her drunk.
你还没见她喝醉酒的样子呢
Bobby?
Bobby?
I found him crying in the fetal position.
我发现他抱着膝盖坐地痛哭
It's not a new symptom.
这不是新症状
He's crying because his liver failure threw his hormones out of whack.
他哭是因为肝脏衰竭让他的荷尔蒙乱了套
Aside from the crying, he's actually recovering nicely.
除了哭 其他方面都恢复得挺好
Aside from the guy in the book depository, the Kennedys had a lovely trip to Dallas.
除了教科书仓库那人之外 肯尼迪一家的达拉斯之旅还不错呢 (指肯尼迪被仓库员工Lee Oswald刺杀的事件)
Repetitive blows to the head can cause chronic traumatic encephalopathy,
反复撞击头部会引起大脑的慢性损伤
symptoms of which are aggressive behavior and depression.
其症状包括富有攻击性的行为及抑郁症
So your theory is that his aggressive behavior caused his aggressive behavior.
于是你的理论是 他的攻击性行为造成了他攻击性的行为?
He's not depressed.
而且他也没抑郁
He's just bummed because he knows he's a talentless moron who's only one lost fight
他低落只是因为他意识到自己只是个没有天分的白痴
away from being a barista. I understand that can get to a guy after a while.
再输一次就好去端盘子了 我理解这样久了总会对人心理产生影响的
If he quits being an enforcer, it could save his life.
他不再做击打手才能得救
You don't want to save his life.
你才不想要救他的命
You want to kill his career.
你想毁了他的职业生涯
I moved into Chase's apartment.
我搬过去跟Chase一起住了
He knows. He was staring at our matching cups.
他知道了 他在盯着我们俩一样的杯子看
I told you we should split up.
我就说咱应该分头行动吧
We're not having sex. With each other..
我们没在乱搞 没互相乱搞
Yet. Yes.
- 还没有? - 还没有
Yes?
还没有?
I just mean no one knows the future right now, so we don't really know-
我只是想说没人能预测未来 所以我们不知道...
The only conclusive test for CTE is post-mortem.
唯一能确诊慢性脑部损伤的只有尸体解剖
But an MRI of his brain could reveal white matter disintegrity,
但给他的大脑做MRI可以显示是否有脑白质分解
which is the effect of CTE.
而那是慢性脑损伤的症状
Why? Are you trying to sleep with her?
为毛? 你想和她上床吗?
'Cause the simpler technique is just to ask. I was doing something nice. Mm, no.
- 最简单的方法难道不是问就行了吗? - 我只是想做个好人
Th-mm. No, that doesn't fit.
才不是吧 完全说不通哟
He's only had three concussions since he was ten.
从十岁开始 他只脑震荡过三回
It's not enough to cause CTE.
不足以造成慢性脑损伤
Three reported concussions. These guys are taught in high school how to dupe the tests.
有记载的脑震荡是三次 这些人从高中开始就有人教他们如何在测试里作假
-Guilt? -This is really insulting.
- 是负罪感么? - 这可真侮辱人
It's not guilt. Park is a friend.
不是什么负罪感 Park和我也只是朋友
So it's guilt.
于是就是负罪感咯
Chase convinced you to leave mommy,
Chase鼓动你离开妈咪
and now he feels responsible.
现在他觉得要对你负责了
No MRI. Do a psych eval.
别做MRI了 做个精神评估
If he doesn't start weeping again, send him home.
如果他不再哭哭啼啼了 就送她回家
Dr. Wilson?
Wilson医生?
Duncan.
Duncan
Uh, James.
呃 叫我James吧
Uh, n-n-nice to meet you.
见到你很高兴
It's nice to meet you.
见到你也很高兴
How are you doing?
呃...你还好吗?
Good.
好啊
I got you this.
我给你买的
Thank you. Go ahead.
- 谢谢 - 拆开啊
Okay.
好的
It's got three games built in, but you can download more from the website.
里面有三个游戏 但是网站上还有更多可以下载的
Yeah, I know.
是啊 我知道
You already have one.
你已经有一个了
I can always use a backup.
多一个也没坏处啊
Hi, can I start you with something to drink? Just water, please.
- 你好 要点喝的吗? - 水就好了 谢谢
You got a Gamedeck?
最新的掌机啊?
Way to go, Dad.
不错啊 老爸
According to your psych eval,
从你的精神评估看来
the only thing happier than you is Disneyland.
比你还开心快乐的也就是迪斯尼城堡了
I'm sorry you had to see me like that last night.
抱歉让你看到我昨晚那个样子
I'm just upset about being in the hospital and...
我只是被困在医院里觉得很沮丧所以...
I'm on some weird meds, but they must be working,
我在用的药很奇怪 但一定有效果
because I'm feeling a lot better now.
因为我已经觉得好多了
Depression could be the symptom of a serious illness.
抑郁可能是严重病症的前兆
CTE.
慢性脑部损伤
Yeah, my aunt sends me every article she can find on it.
是啊 我姑姑把所有能找到的关于这个的论文都发给我了
And you know it could kill you. In the long run, like a lot of things.
- 你知道这个是致命的吧? - 很久之后而已 很多东西不都这样
You might be right. And an MRI could confirm that.
你可能说的没错 一个MRI就能确认了
I have enough evidence of head trauma in my file already, so...
我病历里已经有足够的证明脑部创伤的证据了 所以...
My mom said you had trouble maintaining relationships
我妈妈说你没办法
with normal people.
和正常人保持长期的关系
She also said you were a nice guy.
但她也说你是个好人
I always figured she was lying 'cause she didn't want me to hate my deadbeat dad.
我老以为她在说谎 因为她不想让我恨我的混账老爸
I didn't know-
我可不知道...
I- I know... Now.
我知道...刚知道
You're a bright kid. Thanks to you.
- 你是个聪明孩子 - 这得感谢你
Thanks to my mom, I'm also a big, soft-hearted wuss.
而我妈给我的呢 让我成为了一个心软的懦夫
I think you may have gotten that from both of us.
我觉得我们俩身上都有这基因
Uh, I gotta go, but it was really nice meeting you.
我得走了 但真的很高兴见到你
It was nice meeting you, Duncan.
我也很高兴见到你 Duncan
Uh, you want to hang out again?
你想再一起出来玩吗?
Absolutely.
当然啦
Tonight?
就今晚?
Well, I-I- there's, um...
这个嘛 我今晚有...
That would be great. Okay.
- 没问题 - 好的
I'll text you.
我给你发短信
Thank you. How did you talk him into it?
谢谢你了 你怎么说服他的?
He agreed once I promised him anonymity.
我保证让他匿名测试之后他立刻就同意了
Mr. and Mrs. Doe liked the name John apparently.
他没姓的爹娘给他取名叫无名
Unfortunately we just wasted his time and proved House right. Nothing?
- 可惜我们只是浪费时间证明House说对了 - 什么也没有?
What about that? That's an artifact.
- 那是什么? - 那只是个正常生长
That's a density.
不 是异常密集
I know you think I'm convincing myself, but this brain has been hammered for years,
我知道你觉得我只是自说自话 但这个大脑已经被摧残多年
meaning evidence may be subtle, but it's there.
意味着证据可能并不起眼 但一定在那里
Meaning you see what you want to see.
意味着你只看到你想看到的东西
Unless, of course, Chase is an idiot, and I do have brain damage.
除非 Chase是个白痴 而我有脑损伤
Patient's stroking out.
病人出现中风症状了
Chase? Can you get me out of-
Chase? 把我拉出来好不?
Hello?
喂!
The good news is, it's isolated ophthalmoplegia,
好消息是 的确是眼肌分离症
which means you didn't have a stroke. Bad news is, Taub was right.
意味着你没有发生重分布 而坏消息是 Taub说对了
You're still sick. I said "right," not "competent. "
你还是有病 我说你说对了 没说你有本事
Bursts your CTE bubble.
戳破了你慢性脑损伤的小泡泡
You're going to need a whole new theory to keep Uncle Jesse
你得在想出个新理论才能让Jesse叔叔
and his Olsen twins on the bench.
和奥尔森姐妹继续呆在板凳上 (指电视剧Full House)
Can we discuss my incompetence somewhere else?
我们能不能换个地方讨论我的无能?
Dr. House. Could I talk to you for a minute?
House医生 我能和你单独谈一下吗?
Could be neurosyphilis. He's only 22.
- 可能是神经性梅毒 - 他只有22岁
And he's been on the road since he was 14.
他从14岁起就到处打球了
So he was trash even before he was trash?
你认为他在被揍成垃圾之前就已经是垃圾了?
You curious about what he wanted?
好奇他想干什么吗?
I assume he wanted me off the case, and you told him I was hit in the head as a child,
我猜他想让你把我从病例上踢出去 然后你告诉他我小时候脑袋被敲过
and your mother made you promise to take care of me.
你妈让你发誓照顾我一辈子
He was doing what he always does- sticking up for the little guy.
他在做他一直在做的事: 替小个子出头
He told me to apologize to you,
他告诉我跟你道歉
or he would excrete down my throat.
要不然就朝我的喉咙排泄
I'm paraphrasing.
我这是引用哟
So if he should ask, I was a gentleman,
所以如果他问起 我是个十足的绅士
or I will excrete down your throat.
否则我就往你的喉咙里排泄
Microscopic polyangiitis fits.
毛细血管炎符合症状
We should start plasmapheresis immediately.
我们应该立即开始血浆置换术
We need to run an ANCA panel to confirm first.
我们应该先做ANCA结果测试以确认
Putting him on plasmapheresis could make him bleed out. MPA can progress quickly.
- 给他上血浆置换可能导致大出血 - 毛细血管炎发展迅速
We may not have time before it reaches his lungs.
我们在病症到达他的肺部之前已经没多少时间了
I think you're right.
我觉得你说得对
Thus confirming my objectivity.
这证明了我的客观公正
Start the treatment.
开始治疗
Miserable yet?
觉得倒霉透顶了没?
He's polite, well-adjusted, and a straight-A student.
他有礼貌 脾气好 还是个全优的学生
Which means he doesn't need you.
这说明他并不需要你
So why don't you get out while the butterfly effect is still in the cocoon stage?
于是你干嘛不在蝴蝶效应还在虫蛹阶段时 就赶紧抽身退出呢?
I'm making him dinner. You don't make an 11-year-old dinner.
- 我今晚给他做晚饭 - 11岁的孩子 做什么晚饭?
You give him a jar of peanut butter.
给他一罐花生酱不就得了?
It'll be fine. I could give this kid a quinoa salad,
没问题的 我就算给他一盘藜菜沙拉
and he would eat it just to be nice.
他也会出于礼貌全部吃光
'Cause he's a gutless placater, just like his dad.
因为他就像他爹一样 是个没有骨气的谄媚鬼
He's nice.
他是个好孩子
This is a terrible idea. Because we like each other?
- 这个主意真是糟透了 - 就因为我们喜欢彼此?
Yes.
没错
'Cause of the statement "we like each other. " You've known him 25 minutes.
就因为这个"喜欢彼此" 你们就认识25分钟而已
All you know about him is that he'd lie about a quinoa salad, whatever the hell that is.
你对他所有的了解不过他能因为一盘藜菜沙拉 撒谎 不管那是个啥玩意
You're jealous of an 11-year-old
你在吃一个11岁孩子的醋
because you are an 11-year-old.
因为你就是个11岁的毛孩子
So tell me about yourself.
跟我说说你自己吧
I mean, you're smart, you're nice, but what else?
你又聪明 又有礼貌 还有呢?
I don't know. I'm a kid.
我也不知道啊 我只是个孩子
Right.
好吧
What are you looking for?
你在找什么?
Nothing.
没找什么
You want... peanut butter?
你想吃...花生酱吗?
Do you have prosciutto?
你家有熏火腿吗?
You like prosciutto?
你喜欢吃熏火腿?
I'm weird. No, no.
- 我太奇怪了 - 不不
I- I like it too. I've got some in the fridge. How about goat cheese?
- 我也喜欢呀 冰箱里就有 - 那山羊乳酪呢?
I love goat cheese.
我爱死山羊乳酪啦
I think that was the best pizza I ever had.
我想那是我吃过最美味的披萨
It was the hint of dijon.
因为里面加了第戎芥末
Do you have any aunts or uncles or grandparents?
你有阿姨啊 叔叔啊或者祖父母什么的吗?
My mom got into some stupid fight with my grandfather. They all kind of cut us off.
我妈妈当年跟我外公大吵了一架 他们都跟我们不怎么来往了
Are you talking to your parents?
你会告诉你的父母吗?
Yes, and they're going to be very surprised
当然 他们见到你会非常惊喜
and excited to meet you. That's awesome.
- 和兴奋的 - 那太棒了
You have arrived at your destination.
目的地已经到达
Well- Thanks for the pizza.
- 那好吧... - 谢谢你请我吃披萨
Sure, sure. It was, uh-
没事 没事 那 呃...
I mean, it was great to spend time with you and-
我是说 和你在一起非常开心 而且...
I love you, Dad.
我爱你 爸爸
Can't be easy doing what you do.
干你这行一定不容易
I mean, do you love it? Is it fun?
我是说 你热爱吗? 干这行有趣吗?
I had my own plastic surgery practice making lots of money,
我以前是自己开整容医院的 赚了很多钱
but I wasn't happy.
但是我并不快乐
It wasn't what I went to med school for.
我上医学院不是为了去给人隆胸
Every winter my dad would flood the backyard and made a rink.
每年冬天我爸爸都会在后院泼水 冻成一个溜冰场
I was Lemieux. My little brother was Gretzky.
我当Lemieux 我弟弟当Gretzky (两人都是加拿大著名冰球选手)
I was good.
我那时很厉害的
I won the NDHA scoring title three years in a row.
我连续三年赢得了北部冰球协会的得分王称号
I kept getting bigger and stronger and better...
我身体变得更加强壮 技术更加得炉火纯青...
till I didn't.
直到我停下来的那一天
Juniors coach told me that,
我的青少年教练告诉我
if I wanted to stay on the team, then I'd have to use my size.
如果我想留在队里 我就必须利用我的身体优势
Every game, I got less and less ice time
每次比赛 我真正打冰球的时间越来越少
until it was all fighting and no hockey.
直到整场比赛都是打架 而不是冰球
I, uh...
我 呃...
There's something going on with my arms.
我的胳膊有点儿不对劲
I can't feel them. I-
我感觉不到它们了 我...
Doctor, I can't feel my arms.
医生 我的胳膊没有知觉了
Patient's arms are now paralyzed. ANCA panel was negative.
病人的胳膊失去知觉了 抗中性粒细胞胞浆抗体检查是阴性的
It's not MPA. Lyme disease could cause paralysis.
- 不是显微镜下多血管炎 - 莱姆病会引起瘫痪
If he was hunting, he'd be exposed to ticks.
如果他打猎的话 他就会接触到虱子
No target rash or cardiac involvement.
可是没有皮疹和心脏方面的症状
Roomies with benefits keeping you up?
同居的炮友让你彻夜无眠?
Cribbage. Played with Park's Popo.
玩牌 跟Park的婆婆一起
Is that two separate events?
这是两件不同的事情吗?
Grandmother.
她外婆
ALS could explain the symptoms. Sensory involvement rules out ALS.
- 肌萎缩性脊髓侧索硬化症可以解释他的症状 - 但是感觉障碍排除了这一点
Okay, yeah. This is interesting. We'll get back to the patient in a second.
好了 这很有趣 我们一会儿再谈病人的事
Your issue is the same as Wilson's, except...
你跟Wilson有相同的问题 只不过...
you're haunted by the pitter-patter of tiny skanks.
你是被你的花花肠子所困扰
You don't feel guilty about getting Park thrown out of her home.
你并不是为害Parker无家可归而感到内疚
You feel guilty about all the women that you've screwed over.
你是为你睡过的所有女人而感到内疚
My mother needs 1,000 bucks for snow tires.
我的母亲需要一千块钱买防滑轮胎
Park's a friend. Popo's fun.
Park是我朋友 婆婆也很有趣
Paralysis has gone from his face to his arms,
瘫痪从他的脸部转移到他的胳膊
meaning it's descending, which is the hallmark of botulism.
意味着症状在下移 这是食物中毒的标志
So it was something he ate. How innocuous.
那就是他的食物有问题喽 多么无趣的想法啊
You've overcome your bias by reversing it.
你通过扭转对他的态度消除了对他的偏见
The only problem is that being in love with a patient
唯一的问题是爱上病人
is just as judgmental as being in hate. We didn't find any contaminated-
就会让你的判断变得可憎 我们没有发现任何受污染的...
No contaminated food. I'm not an idiot.
受污染的食物 我不是白痴
But what if it's not from ingesting but from injecting?
但如果不是吃的东西而是他注射的东西呢?
He was treated for intractable muscle spasms by the team's trainers.
队里的教练给他治疗过顽固性肌肉痉挛
Sometimes they use Botox.
有时他们使用肉毒杆菌
We need to start the antitoxin- The antitoxin could cause anaphylaxis.
- 我们需要给他使用抗毒素 - 抗毒素可能会引发过敏性反应
We need to test first to confirm.
我们需要先做个化验来证实
As if to prove my point, last time you said there wasn't enough time to test
你这正好证明了我的观点 上次在一个更危险的治疗之前
prior to a more dangerous treatment.
你说没时间来化验
It's a different situation, different symptom, different diagnosis.
这次是不一样的情况 不一样的症状 不一样的诊断
Different emotion.
不一样的感情
Give him the antitoxin.
给他用抗毒素
Anything? No adverse effects.
- 还好吗? - 还没出现不良反应
Chase let me move in with him to get away from my grandmother.
Chase让我搬过去 是为了摆脱我外婆
Then he practically let my grandmother move in with the both of us.
然后他又让我外婆搬进来跟我俩住在一起
He's being way more than nice.
他人好得有点儿过头了
Then which answer is it?
那他这么做是为什么?
Chase feels guilty for pushing you to move out? He didn't push me.
- Chase因为强迫你从家里搬出来而感到内疚? - 他没有强迫我
Guilt about skanks? He loves skanks. It's not the other option.
- 因为跟女人乱搞而内疚? - 他喜欢跟人乱搞
People even want to sleep with me. Some of them are even good-looking.
甚至有人想跟我上床 其中一些人长得还是很好看的
That good-looking?
有Chase那么好看吗?
Did you see that?
你看到了吗?
You're feeling something? Yeah.
- 你感觉到什么了吗? - 是的
I could give you crap for making me wait 11 years,
我本可以为你让我等了11年而斥责你
but instead I'm going to thank you
但相反我要感谢你
for not making me wait another 11.
让我没有再等上11年
Every little girl wants a pony till they have to clean up after it.
每个小女孩都想要一匹小马 直到要给它清理粪便
You think I'm going to quit on this? On an 11-year-old?
你认为我会放弃吗? 放弃一个11岁的孩子?
The only relationship you haven't quit on has been with me.
你唯一保持到现在的关系就是跟我
Hmm. A needy, truculent narcissist.
嗯 一个欲求不满 尖酸刻薄的自恋狂
I think it's been perfect training for parenthood.
我想这是对为人父母的绝佳训练
That's not even close.
根本是两码事
This is the rest of your life.
这是关系到你后半辈子的事情
You screw this up, you don't get to run away.
你搞砸的话 不能拍拍屁股走人
You get to ruin both your lives.
你会毁掉你们两个人的生活的
This is a bigger responsibility than any you've ever taken on
这比你以往担负和搞砸的责任
and screwed up.
都更加沉重
I know.
我知道
That's why I'm so excited about it.
所以我对此感到激动万分
You're really happier doing this than looking at boobs all day?
你干这行真的比整天看别人胸部要来得快乐吗?
Luckily I get patients like you every now and again
幸运的是我经常会遇到像你这样的病人
who let me reexperience the joy.
让我一遍又一遍地感到快乐
You know, the best part of my day is when I'm sitting
你知道 我一天最好的时光就是
in that penalty box after I beat someone up.
在我暴打别人一顿后坐在受罚席的时候
That's the only time I know I'm safe.
那是我知道自己是安全的唯一时间
Think Lemieux ever felt that way?
你觉得Lemieux也有过这种感觉吗?
I'm not going back. To hockey?
- 我不会回去的 - 回去打冰球?
To enforcing... Whatever that costs.
去靠打架比赛... 不管付出什么代价
Good for you.
这是好事儿
First goal for the pocket rocket.
口袋火箭队的第一粒进球
Bobby?
Bobby?
We need a team in here!
快来人啊!
He's completely paralyzed, and he tested negative for botulism.
他完全瘫痪了 食物中毒化验是阴性的
I am now accepting long shots.
不管风险大或小 畅所欲言吧
Polio.
小儿麻痹症
Some kids were never vaccinated.
有些孩子从来没打过疫苗
Unless they played sports all their lives and had two physicals a year.
除了那些一直在从事体育行业 而且一年进行两次体检的
How about MLD? That's a bad fit.
- 异染性脑白质营养不良呢? - 症状不符合
I say that not because there's no treatment for MLD
我这么说不是因为异染性脑白质营养不良 是治不好的
but because it's a bad fit. His cognitive abilities are unaffected.
而是因为症状不符合 他的认知能力没有受到影响
Prion disease could explain the waxing and waning symptoms.
朊病毒病可以解释这种忽好忽坏的症状
The test for Prions is a brain biopsy.
可要检查朊病毒病就要进行大脑切片检查
Given his history, there's got to be brain swelling.
鉴于他的病史 他现在一定有脑肿胀
We can't risk drilling into his skull. Pretty sure we can.
- 我们不能冒险来钻开他的大脑 - 我们当然可以
We also could keep talking until we can find an answer we all can agree on.
那我们也可以一直讨论 直到找到一个我们都同意的答案
All of us?
我们所有的人吗?
Those who love him, those who hate him, those who don't give a crap about him or you-
那些爱他的人 那些恨他的人 还有那些不在乎他或者你的人
Or I could just discuss it on my own with Foreman.
或者我可以自己去找Foreman谈
He's not your friend. I get it.
- 他不是你的朋友 - 我明白了
He's a patient. I'm not- He never had your back.
- 他是个病人 我没有... - 他从来没支持过你
He didn't insist that I apologize to you.
他没有坚持让我给你道歉
He asked me to take you off the case.
他让我把你从这个病例里踢出去
Biopsy his brain.
去给他大脑做活检
Hey, Dad.
嘿 爸爸
Sorry I'm late. Got in a fight with my mom.
抱歉我来晚了 我跟我妈妈吵了一架
She's such a tool. I'm sure she means well.
- 她简直就是个白痴 - 我知道她肯定是好意
She wants to open a reserve in Costa Rica
她想在哥斯达黎加弄一个自然保护区
for rescued birds of prey.
来拯救食肉鸟
But how serious is she?
但是她有多认真呢?
From my recollection, she used to talk about doing a lot-
就我的了解 她以前总是说要做很多事情...
Yeah, but she bought plane tickets for Monday.
是 可她已经买好周一的机票了
Well, Costa Rica is beautiful.
好吧 哥斯达黎加风景很好
And the schools are supposed to be great. Oh, I'm not going.
- 而且学校也应该不错 - 我不会去的
It's her stupid dream, not mine.
那是她愚蠢的梦想 不是我的
Then what will you do?
那你要怎么办?
I- I thought maybe I could, uh...
我想也许我可以 呃...
Maybe I could stay with you?
也许我可以和你一起生活?
Uh, y-your place is only 3 miles away from my school.
你家离我的学校只有3英里远
I could bus it every day. And I do my own laundry.
我可以每天乘公车上下学 而且我可以自己洗衣服
I keep my room tidy.
我会自己整理自己的屋子
Duncan, th-this-
Duncan 这...
This is very sudden.
这太突然了
I know.
我知道
I'm sorry.
对不起
Please don't send me to the jungle.
求你不要让我去热带雨林
If it's okay with your mother, it's okay with me.
如果你妈妈同意的话 那我没问题
Take me off the case.
把我从这个病例中剔除掉吧
I've obviously completely lost my objectivity.
很显然我已经丧失掉我的客观性了
I'm not helping, I'm not even neutral.
这件事上我毫无用处 甚至都做不到中立
Agreed.
完全同意
So why shouldn't I take you off all my cases?
那我何不把你从我所有的病例中都剔除掉呢?
Because you were right. I hate bullies.
因为你是对的 我讨厌恃强凌弱的人
You work for me. You're not a bully.
- 可你为我工作 - 你不是恃强凌弱的人
Pretty sure I am, dickwad.
我当然是 伙计
I've known a lot of bullies- people who didn't like me because I'm short,
我认识很多恃强凌弱的人 人们不喜欢我因为我矮
people who didn't like me because I'm Jewish- Yeah, I get it.
- 人们不喜欢我因为我是犹太人 - 好吧 我明白了
There's a long list of reasons not to like you.
人们不喜欢你有很多原因
You relentlessly mock, but it's not for self-aggrandizement.
你无情的嘲讽一切 但不是为了增强自己的重要性
It's because ideas are bigger than feelings.
而是因为想法比感受更重要
At least that's what I choose to believe.
至少这是我选择相信的
I also thought you had the side effect of desensitizing me.
我同时认为你麻木我的情感是有副作用的
You little Hebe.
你这个犹太小人儿
Here's some ideas for you. You screwed up.
给你几点忠告 你搞砸事情
You kept on screwing up. Everything you said is true,
你总是搞砸事情 你说的都对
except...
除了...
It doesn't mean you walk away.
这不意味着你可以一走了之
You just learn to trust nothing.
你得学会不相信任何事情
Everything you think you feel,
所有你认为你感受到的情感
everything you think you know.
所有你认为你知道的事情
Question every call, play through every whistle.
质疑每通电话 注意每次的警笛
I just had a light bulb. Maybe.
我刚刚灵光一现 也许是
You can trust light bulbs.
你可以相信灵感
Stop.
住手
It's not Prions. Epstein-Barr gave him mono.
不是朊病毒 Epstein-Barr病毒使他 患上了单核细胞增多症
It also gave him Miller Fisher syndrome.
同时也让他患上Miller Fisher综合症
The plasmapheresis played through the whistle.
血浆除去法发出了警笛
We gave it to him for MPA, but when he got worse, we took him off.
我们以此来治疗他的显微镜下多血管炎 但情况变糟后 就没有给他继续用这个治疗
When he got better, we thought it was the antitoxin.
当他情况好转以后 我们认为是抗毒素的作用
But it was actually the plasmapheresis still working.
但实际上是血浆除去治疗的作用
We had the right treatment, just the wrong diagnosis.
我们治疗方案没错 只是诊断错了
It was my metaphor that solved the case.
是我的隐喻解决了病案
Put him back on plasmapheresis. He'll be fine.
给他继续用血浆除去法治疗 他会好起来的
Nice save.
干得不错
Didn't quite make up for being a sieve the rest of the game.
但弥补不了你其余时间只当筛子的错误
Ex-girlfriend's baby again?
又忙着照顾前女友的孩子了?
His mother is moving to Costa Rica.
他妈妈要搬去哥斯达黎加了
He asked if he could move in with me.
他问我能不能搬过来跟我一起住
And I said yes.
然后我同意了
Well, it's only six or seven years.
不过六七年而已
Unless he can't get into college, in which case, it's more a matter of your life expectancy.
除非他上不了大学 不过 这更加取决于你活不活得了那么久
I said yes, knowing I'm not remotely ready for that,
我虽然同意了 但我知道我远没有准备好
knowing he's not ready to be separated from his mother.
知道他没准备好和他母亲分开
This isn't the act of a mature, rational adult.
这不是一个成熟理性的成年人该有的举动
I-
我...
I can't do this, House.
我做不到 House
You were right.
你说得对
I have an idea... that can make this entire problem go away.
我有个主意... 可以让这所有的麻烦烟消云散
Yes, I really want to hear your clever late-term abortion joke.
是的 我非常想听听 你那聪明的怀孕末期流产的笑话
You were right about everything. This is life. It's real.
你对一切的看法都是对的 这是人生 这都是真的
It doesn't just go away.
不会凭空消失
None of that is true.
这一切都不是真的
Duncan.
Duncan
Actually... Wendel.
事实上是... Wendel
One "I."
一个"L"
If you're going to get pissy,
如果你要生气的话
remember, it was House's idea.
记住 这都是House的主意
You're an actor?
你是个演员?
Five commercials and a recurring on Days of Our Lives.
拍过五个广告 在"我们生活的日子"中演过一个循环角色
You were regretting not having kids, so I gave you one...
你后悔没有孩子 所以我给了你一个...
Thereby rendering you regret-free.
这样你就再也用不着后悔了
It's a priceless gift.
这是一个无价的礼物
Get out. Well, it's not priceless 'cause he charges SAG minimum.
- 滚出去 - 也不是无价啦 因为他收取了演员工会的最低价
Get out!
滚出去!
Chillax, Dad.
冷静 爸爸
Can you do an Australian accent?
你能模仿澳大利亚口音吗?
I just got the call.
我接到了一个电话
Three-year deal. $2.1 million.
三年合约 210万
What about the flooded backyard and pretending to be Lemieux?
那你结冰的后院和假装Lemieux的梦想呢?
That's why I took it.
我正是为此才接受的
After all I did to get here,
我好不容易走到了今天
half a dream is better than nothing.
实现半个梦想比什么都没有要强得多
Maybe my new coach will see what my juniors coach didn't.
也许新教练会看到青少年教练没有看到的闪光点
That'd be nice.
那可是不错
I'm not sleeping with you.
我不会跟你上床的
That's a shame.
真遗憾啊
This is about Popo.
是因为婆婆
She's not sleeping with me either, right?
她也不会跟我上床的 对吧?
You were jealous of me.
你嫉妒我
My family.
我的家庭
Maybe you've got too much, and I've got too little.
也许你拥有的太多 而我拥有的太少
I might sleep with you after all.
不过我没准会跟你上床呢
The woman that I called- that was really Beth?
我打电话过去的那个女的 她真的是Beth吗?
Found her on Facebook.
我在脸书上找到的她
How much did she charge?
她要了你多少钱?
Nothing. She's still pissed at you.
分文未取 她还对你心存怨念呢
that's???
那是培根
I thought you liked prosciutto.
我还以为你喜欢熏火腿呢
Nobody likes prosciutto.
哪有人会喜欢熏火腿啊
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入